Guide to the Presidential Autographs, 1794-1954 M0005
Department of Special Collections and University Archives
Presidential Autographs,
1794-1954
M0005
Department of Special Collections and University Archives
18.0 Items
SCOPE AND CONTENT
Letters, notes, and documents bearing presidential autographs representing a range from a military return for rations signed by William Henry Harrison (1794) to a copy of a speech given by Dwight D. Eisenhower (1954).
Provenance:
Donative purchase, Mr. and Mrs. Albert C. Beeson, 1967
Access Restrictions:
None.
- Adams, John Quincy., 1820 March 2; 1; LS, 2 pages (Box 1)
  Scope and Contents note
  A letter written to a State Department auditor regarding the rates of commission to be allowed Col. Aspinwall, Consul of the US at London, on his disbursements.
- Arthur, Chester A., 1872 May 22; 2; ANS, 1 page (Box 1)
  A short note giving the present address of Mr. H. J. Haynsworth.
- Buchanan, James., n.d.; 3; LS, 2 pages (Box 1)
  A letter to the President signed by James Buchanan as the first signature as well as other members of the Pennsylvania delegation in Congress. A recommendation to the President on behalf of Thomas Walter of Philadelphia who had recently been a doorkeeper of the House of Representatives of Pennsylvania.
- Eisenhower, Dwight D., 1954 Jan. 7; 4; DS, 12 pages (Box 1)
  A mimeographed copy of Pres. Eisenhower's speech delivered to the Joint Session of the 83rd Congress.
- Fillmore, Millard., 1848 July 1; 5; DS, 2 pages (Box 1)
  Hudson and Berkshire Rail-road Co. Bond in the amount of $1000. Countersigned by Fillmore as Comptroller of New York state.
- Garfield, James A., 1870; 6; ADS, 1 page (Box 1)
  Garfield's retained copy of a telegram to the Assistant Secretary of the Treasury about the Geneva awards entry upon the Treasury books.
- Harrison, William Henry., 1794 July 28; 7; ANS, 2 pages (Box 1)
  A military return for rations.
- Hayes, Rutherford B., 1878 Jan. 26; 8; ANS on carte-de-visite, 1 page (Box 1)
  Brief note written by Hayes as President endorsing a Col. Higgins as a man of character.
- Jackson, Andrew., 9; ANS, 4 pages (Box 1)
  An endorsement by Jackson on verso of last page of a letter written to James Buchanan, then a member of Congress, "referring to the Secretary of War to be read before him.. ."
- Johnson, Andrew., 1856 May 21; 10; DS, 1 page (Box 1)
  Printed commission for a Justice of Peace signed by Johnson while Governor of Tennessee. Countersigned by the Sec'y. of State, Tenn.
- Madison, James., 1816 June 27; 11; DS, 2 pages (Box 1)
  A printed land grant signed by Madison and Josiah Meigs, Commissioner of the General Land Office, granting a quarter section to a Kentucky resident.
- McKinley, William., n.d.; 12; ADS, 1 page (Box 1)
  A document to the Interior Dept. asking the full name and regiment of a Bixler.
- Monroe, James., 1815 Nov. 16; 13; AL, 1 page (Box 1)
  Regrets from Monroe to Mr. Gray for not having had time to fulfill a promise.
- Pierce, Franklin., 1851 Feb. 1; 14; ALS, 2 pages (Box 1)
  A letter regarding a legal matter, advising "it will be your duty to take a physician's certificate showing his [father's] condition and the case will be continuted.. ."
- Polk, James K., 1847 July 12; 15; AL, 1 page (Box 1)
  A letter in the third person requesting the presence of Governor and Mrs. Morey at dinner.
- Taylor, Zachary., 1823 March 4; 16; ALS, 2 pages (Box 1)
  A letter regarding a trial, giving legal advice that if the Captain concerned recalls a certain instance it will prove that "Col. Arbuckle was induced from personal motives to exchange the Companies as he did not for the public good.. ."
- Tyler, John., 1859 March 7; 17; LS, 1 page (Box 1)
  A printed form letter to which Tyler has added five lines and his signature. Written to Union College, concerning the fire and burning of William and Mary College which destroyed the library.
- Van Buren, Martin., 1829 Jan. 5; 18; ALS, 2 pages (Box 1)
  Expression of regret that he will be unable to meet friends in the evening.